Guide to the National Association of Science Writers and Council for the Advancement of Science Writing records, 1934-2018
National Association of Science Writers and Council for the Advancement of Science Writing records, 1934-2018
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
National Association of Science Writers and Council for the Advancement of Science Writing records, 1934-2018.
4448
National Association of Science Writers.
33 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the National Association of Science Writers and the Council for the Advancement of Science Writing include correspondence, membership records, financial records, domestic and international affairs material, newsletters, administrative material, working papers for seminars and workshops, samples of science writing, papers and theses, published reports, and video and audiocassettes. Correspondents include Earl Ubell, William J. Cromie, Pierre Fraley, Philip M. Boffey, Jane Stafford, and Herbert L. Nichols. Organizations mentioned include the American Association for the Advancement of Science and the Ford Foundation.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The National Association of Science Writers (NASW) is a professional society, established in 1934, serving science journalists and public information specialists. The Council for the Advancement of Science Writing (CASW), which was created in 1960, is a non-profit organization that sponsors various activities intended to improve the quality and quantity of information about science that reaches the public.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the National Association of Science Writers and the Council for the Advancement of Science Writing include correspondence, membership records, financial records, domestic and international affairs material, newsletters, administrative material, working papers for seminars and workshops, samples of science writing, papers and theses, published reports, and video and audiocassettes. Correspondents include Earl Ubell, William J. Cromie, Pierre Fraley, Philip M. Boffey, Jane Stafford, and Herbert L. Nichols. Organizations mentioned include the American Association for the Advancement of Science and the Ford Foundation.
Also, oral history interview with Jane Stafford by Bruce Lewenstein, 1987.
SUBJECTS
Names:
National Association of Science Writers.; Boffey, Philip M.; Cromie, William J.; Fraley, Pierre.; Lewenstein, Bruce V.,; Nichols, Herbert L.(Herbert Lownds), 1908-; Stafford, Jane.; Ubell, Earl.; American Association for the Advancement of Science.; Council for the Advancement of Science Writing.; Council for the Advancement of Science Writing.; Ford Foundation.; National Association of Science Writers.
Subjects:
Science news--United States.; Communication in science--United States.; Journalism--United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audio tapes.; Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Series I. General files
Series II. Series II. International Affairs
Series III. Series III. Dometic Affairs
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a copy of the printed finding aid. PDF file.
  Not all the material in the collection is covered by the above guide.
- Series I. General files
  This collection was originally compiled without series. A later addition was split into International Affairs material and Domestic material, thus Series II and Series III were created. Everything listed under Series I represents the original list and may contain material that belongs in Series II and III.
  - Publications and unpublished articles, 19-19 (Box 32)
  - Conference files, 1984-1999 (Box 32)
  - Awards files, 1989-2000 (Box 32)
  - Awards files, 1993-2000 (Box 33)
  - Fellowship files: Haseltine, 1987-1990 (Box 33)
  - Fellowship files: Kellogg, 1990-1996 (Box 33)
  - Fellowship files: NASW-Duke University, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Fellowship files: Ullman, 1983 (Box 33)
  - Press release, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Jane Stafford Oral History, 1989 (Box 33)
  - Press Room Book, 1992 (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1984-1996 (Box 33)
  - External correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 33)
  - Poster from University of California, Santa Cruz (Box 33)
  - NASW LOGO Designs (Box 33)
  - Letterhead and blank certificates (Box 33)
  - American Chemical Society/Victor Cohn’s Presentation/October 15, 1999 (videotape) (Box 33)
  - General Meeting/Excom/ New Orleans, 2/17/1990; The New York Academy of Sciences, Panels 1 & 2, 9/27/1994; The Osgood File/Network Access Project IV, 1998, 1990, 1994, 1998 (Box 33)
  - Science Writing Survey, 1977-1992 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - CASW Report and correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Washington Independent Writers: directory of members, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Membership rosters and miscellaneous, 1982-2004 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - NASW directories of members, 1982, 1986-1990, 1992-1993 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Agenda, 1984-1986 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - CASW meeting minutes, 1986-1996 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - CASW - Traveling Fellowship Committee, 1987-1992 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Science Writing Survey, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - New Horizons in Science proposal file copy, 1988-1990 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - NSF correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Agricultural Travel Fellowship Program, 1990-1991 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Kellogg/report final letter/budget, 1990-1993 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - CASW Agriculture Fellowships - applicants, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Society of Environmental Journalists (SEJ): membership directories, 1991, 1992, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Agriculture articles and publicity, 1991-1995 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - CASW Annual Briefing: New Horizons in Science, 1991-2004 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - CASW Bio's 1992 election, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Kellogg - Africa, 1994-1995 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - NASW Membership Directories, 1994, 1996-1997 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Mass Media Fellows: Directory, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - SEJ: membership directories, 1995-1996 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - CASW programs and activities, 1997-1999 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - SEJ: membership directories, 1997-1999 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - NASW membership directories and resource guides, 1999-2001 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Science-in-Society journalism awards, 2000 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - NASW membership directory and resource guide, 2001 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - NASW membership directory and resource guide, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - NOVA/Secrets, Lies, and Atomic Spies, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - NASW Science in Society Journalism Award Winners, 2007 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - NASW Science in Society Journalism Award Winners: Beth Whitehouse, “The Match”, 2007 (Box 34, Folder 31)
  - NASW Science in Society Journalism Award Winners: Stephen Lyons and Llewellyn M. Smith, Forgotten Genius. DVD, 2007; 483 (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - NASW Science in Society Journalism Award Winners: Alison Richard and David Malakoff, Climate Connections: How People Change Climate, How Climate Changes People. 2 CDs, 2007; 423, 425 (Box 34, Folder 34)
  - Brochures from NASW events, 2013-2014 (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - CASW awards, 2000-2004 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - News and Numbers, Victor Cohn, 1989, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Victor Cohn prize: nomination Shannon Brownlee, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Victor Cohn prize: nomination Christine Gorman, 2004 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Victor Cohn prize: nomination Daniel Haney, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Victor Cohn prize: nomination Michelle Trudeau, 2 CD-ROM, 2004; 420 (Box 35, Folder 6-7)
  - Victor Cohn prize: nomination Jeff Wheelwright, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Evolution t.v. series: "Darwin's Dangerous Idea" (drama script), 2001 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Engineering and Life, 2 CD-ROM, 2002; 421 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Bloodlines: Technology Hits Home, CD-ROM, 2003; 422 (Box 35, Folder 11-12)
  - Bloodlines: Technology Hits Home, videotape, 2003 (Box 35)
  - Building a New Child.. .. and Free to Be Me, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Science in Society journalism awards, 2000, 2002-2004 (Box 35, Folder 14-18)
  - NASW Roster of Members, 1982-1983, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - NASW membership directory, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - NASW membership directory, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - NASW membership directory, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Evolution t.v. series: 7 videotapes [7 programs], 2001 (Box 35)
    - Evolution shows 1: Darwin's Dangerous Idea, V-1359 (Box 35)
    - Evolution shows 2: Great Transformations, V-1360 (Box 35)
    - Evolution shows 3: Extinction, V-1361 (Box 35)
    - Evolution shows 4: Evolutionary Arms Race, V-1362 (Box 35)
    - Evolution shows 5: Why Sex?, V-1363 (Box 35)
    - Evolution shows 6: The Mind's Big Bang, V-1364 (Box 35)
    - Evolution shows 7: What About God?, V-1365 (Box 35)
  - Bloodlines: Technology Hits Home, 2003; V-1366 (Box 35)
  - NASW workshops (12 audio cassettes), 2001; 8270a-8281a (Box 35)
  - Directory of Science Communication Courses and Programs in U.S.A., 1993 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Victor Cohn Award nomination: Laurie Garrett, 2000 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Victor Cohn Award nomination: Dan Fagin, 2002 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - NASW Newsletter - ScienceWriters, 1993-2018 (Box 37)
  - Membership lists and directories, 1977, 1979, 1982-1983, 1988, 1991, 1993-1995, 1997-2008, 1977-2008 (Box 38, Folder 1-15)
  - Science in Journalism leaflets, 1979, 1985-1990, l992-1993, 1995-2002, 2004-2007, 1979-2007 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Membership recruitment leaflets, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Membership cards, 2007-2008 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - A Guide to Careers in Science Writing, [1998] (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - "Engineering and Life" [CD] (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Science journalism schools/courses, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Science Writers Awards, 1990, 1992, 1993, 2005, 1990-2005 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Award winner, 2003: "Bloodlines" [V-1099 and CD-315] (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - A Field Guide for Science Writers, Deborah Blum, Mary Knudson, and Robin Morantz Henig (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Communicating Science News, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - "Physics Today", 1979-03 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Science-in-Society Journalism Awards, 1987-2005 (Box 38, Folder 21-24)
  - Tribute to the publication Mosaic, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    Fall
  - Conference session audio tapes (first copies), 1998-2001 (Box 39)
  - Conference session audio tapes (use copies) [not complete], 1998-2001 (Box 40)
  - NASW membership list (2), 1978 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - The Writer magazine essay contest forms (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Ballot, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - NASW certificates (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Council of Writers Organization [now defunct] (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - 50th Anniversary, 2010 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - CASW miscellaneous (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - NASW Miscellaneous (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - CASW 50th token of appreciation to guests and speakers (Box 38)
  - Locations of New Horizons in Science meetings, 1974-2000 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence concerning the location of New Horizons in Science meetings, 1989-2015 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - New Horizons in Science, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    13th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    27th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    29th Annual Briefing
  - Study of the New Horizons in Science Briefing, 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - New Horizons in Science, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    30th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    31st Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    32nd Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    33rd Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    34th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    35th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    36th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    37th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    38th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2001 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    39th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2002 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    40th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2003 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    41st Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2004 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    42nd Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    43rd Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2006 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    44th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2007 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    45th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2008 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    46th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2009 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    47th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2010 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    48th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2011 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    49th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2012 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    50th Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science, 2013 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    51st Annual Briefing
  - New Horizons in Science Programs, 2014-2017 (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Summary of Programs and Activities, 1985-1999 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Summary of Programs and Activities, 2000-2015 (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1984-1989 (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1990-2004 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2005-2017 (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - CASW Guidelines, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Bylaws, 1961-2002 (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - CASW membership biographies, 1983-1999 (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Ben Patrusky biographical material, 1985-2008 (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - CASW Bibliographies, 1980-1989 (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - CASW website, 2001 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - American Tentative Society (ATS) material concerning fellows and the society, 1981-1995 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence concerning the future planning of CASW, 1984-2008 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2011 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence and articles - David Zimmerman, 1993-1997 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Letters of Appreciation to Jerry Bishop, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 40)
  - CASW's traveling guru program, 1980-1999 (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - CASW Agricultural Travel Program for Science Journalists to Sub-Saharan Africa Final Report, 1995-06 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Science Writers questionnaires, 1958-1985 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Sciencewriters newsletter proposal and history, 1989-2015 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Victor Cohn Award, 1995-2004 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Victor Cohn Award, 2005-2017 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Victor Cohn Award winners, 2005-2008 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Victor Cohn Award winners, 2010-2013 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - News and Numbers: A Guide to Reporting Statistical Claims and Controversies in Health and Other Fields by Victor Cohn, 1989, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - News and Numbers: A Guide to Reporting Statistical Claims and Controversies in Health and Other Fields by Victor Cohn, 2012 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Taylor/Blakeslee Graduate Fellowship, 1988-2008 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Burroughs Wellcome Fund, 1998-2008 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Founder's Fund, 1996-2000 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Brinson Foundation, 2007--2008 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Barbara Trevett Fund, 2011-2013 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Evert Clark/Seth Payne Award, 2013-2014 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Award reception programs, 2003-2013 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Directory of Science Communication Courses and Programs in the United States, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Guide to Careers in Science Writing, 1997 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - CASW Audits, 1987-1996 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    Missing 1983, 1987, 1988
  - Financial Statements, 1982-2015 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Tax returns, 1988-2002 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    Missing 1990, 1991, 1993
  - Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Dues Forms, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - ISWA Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - General ISWA, 1998-2004 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Spanish Invitation, Undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - ISWA Constitution, 1972-1987 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - ISWA Aims (French, Undated (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Russian "Application", Undated (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Russian "Aims", Undated (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Applications, Undated (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - ISWA 94 Correspondence, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - 96 Correspondence, 1996 (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Membership and dues Correspondence, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Applicants, 1980-1998 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Applicants, 1989-1998 (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Applicants and Member Acceptance Letters, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Member Rosters, 1976-2001 (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - 4th World Conference of Science Journalists Final Program, 2004 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Brazil 3rd World Conference of Science Journalism (WCSJ) Formal "Founding" of WFSJ (World Federation of Science Journalism), 2002 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - 2nd WCSJ Budapest, Hungary, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Green Press, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Unreported Stories: Mass Media and Science in the Developing World, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - 2nd WCSJ Budapest, Hungary, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - 8th WCSJ Hesinki, Finland, 2013 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - 5th WCSJ Melbourne, Australia, 2006-2007 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - 4th WCSJ Montreal Ratification of WFSJ, 2004 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Technical meetings and Symposium Proceedings ISWA, 1986-1991 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Japan "Interim WCSJ" First Formulation of WFSJ, 2001-2002 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - IBERO - AM Conference Madrid, Spain (Precursor to WCSJ), 1977 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Bellagio residency application, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - 2nd WCSJ Budapest, Hungary, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - National Association of Science Writers Newsletter, 1998 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - ISWA Membership Roster, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Science, Media and Popular Delusions Pugwash Conference, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - First WCSJ Program and Proceedings, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - First WCSJ Sessions, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - 1st WCSJ Tokyo, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 28)
- Series II. International Affairs
  - International Geosphere-Biosphere Programme (IGBP) Paris, 1992-09 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Public Communication of Science and Technology (PCST) Madrid, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Korea Folder 1 of 2, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Korea Science Foundation Folder 2 of 2, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - PCST Madrid '91, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Brazil "Greenpress", 1992 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - 2000 China (Aborted), 2000 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - 5th International Conference on PCST Delegates Manual, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Pan-Africa Conference (Proposed only), 1994-1995 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - PCST Montreal April '94, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Costa Rica, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Ciencia Cierta, 1990-1992 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Arbol, 1990-1992 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Brazil "Press + Planet" ISWA (International Science Writers Association) and USIS (United States Information Service) INPE (Instituto de Pesquisas Especiais) 1 of 6, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Brazil "Press + Planet" ISWA and USIS IBAMA Trip 2 of 6, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Brazil "Press + Planet" ISWA and USIS Seminar 3 of 6, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Brazil "Press + Planet" ISWA and USIS Clips 4 of 6, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Brazil "Press + Planet" ISWA and USIS Clips 5 of 6, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Brazil "Press + Planet" ISWA and USIS Correspondence 6 of 6, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Valencia 5th IBERO American Conference, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Spain 11/19-28 PCST MTG J. Cornell Notebook, 1990-11-21-1990-12-10 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Spain, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Bogota, Colombia, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - ISY (International Space Year)/ICSU (International Council of Scientific Unions)/Report "International Space Year" Planning, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Indonesia Rain Forest Seminar Proposed Only, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - V Congreso Iberoamericano, 1990-1991 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) and ISWA, 1974-1975 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - International Activities, 1969-1985 (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - American University in Cairo (AUC), 1973-1977 (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - ISWA Newsletters Complete Set 1 of 2, 1975-1987 (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - ISWA Newsletters Complete Set 2 of 2, 1987-1998 (Box 44, Folder 31)
  - ISWA Mailing List, Constitution, Correspondence, 1979-1987 (Box 44, Folder 32)
  - 3rd World Resources, 1986-1988 (Box 44, Folder 33)
  - India Proposal Only Failed, 1987-1989 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Caracas, Venezuela UNESCO 7/81, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Switzerland ICSU, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Interciencia, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - India USIS/SI ISWA, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 5)
- Series III. Dometic Affairs
  - Correspondence and Science Articles, 1985-1991 (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Foundations, 1990-2001 (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - MacArthur Foundation Grant, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - ISWA Seminar Originals, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 30)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) Correspondence, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 31)
  - AAAS, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 32)
  - AAAS, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 33)
  - AAAS Latin America, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 34)
  - Workshop Proceedings ISWA, 1985-1986 (Box 45, Folder 35)
  - BOSTID Developments Newsletter, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 36)
  - International Environmental Reporting, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 37)
  - The Johnson Foundation Wingspread Conference, 1987-1988 (Box 45, Folder 38)
  - AAAS/ISWA Proceedings, 1985-1986 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - AAAS, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - AAAS/ISWA Boston Meeting Reception 2/12/88, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - AAAS, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - AAAS, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - AAAS/ISWA Technical Session Advocacy Journalism, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - National Association of Science Writers Newsletter, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - ISWA annual meeting NYC Photos, 1984-05-27 (Box 43, Folder 8)